[Music]
welcome to a new episode of what's
cooking today we'll be looking at a code
contribution that actually almost was
two years in the making back in 20123 I
only decided that it was time to create
an API that makes it easier to store
your data outside of business Central
for instance in an Azure blob storage
Azure file share or SharePoint
online so he went ahead and created a
system application module that allows it
to connect to these external file
storage
systems now with 2025 wave 1 this new
SST application module is ready for
release it is important to notice that
there is no uptake of it yet so the base
application as such does not use it but
you as a developer can use this new API
to easily store data outside of business
Central
as this is a what's cooking uh recording
we are mostly going to give you a teaser
here so this is not like a thorough
in-depth review of the API um but let me
just show you what this new capability
looks like when it
ships so here in business Central if you
go into file
accounts you'll see a view that is
actually familiar to you to you maybe
from the email accounts it's kind of
built up in the same pattern if you will
um so in here you
can um set up a file account for Block
storage file share or SharePoint for the
sake of this demo let's just use blob
storage so we're going to enter a name
can be any name then we need the storage
account name of the blob storage you
want to connect to in this case it's my
yes special BL storage I use the share
key which I paste in and here I can just
scroll down to find my container and
that's really all it
takes now um we can look at file
scenarios just like we have them in
email scenarios given we only have a
single account of course it's the
default and given there is uh no uptake
there are no scenarios
yet all right so now we can actually
start using this uh and for that I've
had a short a little code snippet here
um so we're just going to add an action
uh to which saves the order confirmation
uh on the sales order
page and we extend the file scenario
enum with our scenario which is save the
order
confirmation and then the code that we
need to
actually um save the file is rather
simple so first we create a PDF file
that doesn't really have anything to do
with this feature we just create the
file and now what we need to to store
the this file is that we initialize our
external file file storage um with our
scenario um we open a file a save file
dialogue to get the path where on the uh
Azure blob St we want to save it and
then we invoke create
file and that is it with this code these
two lines um we can now store a file
outside of business Central so we now
have the file scenario we can say that
there the save order confirmation uh
should be stored in a blob
storage and now if we go into a sales
order we open the sales order we can
find the action that our little app
introduced which was save order
confirmation and when we invoke this
action we get the file dialogue so let's
just save it in the root folder here of
our blob storage and call it
test and that's it uh now when we go to
file accounts and we open the new
storage browser we can see that our test
PDF was put into our account
and there we have
it so that's pretty powerful stuff um of
course we will be looking into uptaking
some of these capabilities in business
Central in the upcoming waves but we
didn't want to hold this back um from
you I mean this is ready to be used so
go ahead and enjoy this new API and
store your files outside of business
Central thanks for listening